<blog>
	<post>
		<id>1</id>
		<date>4/20/2023</date>
		<author>Natasha Malone</author>
		<title>Building the Pathway: U.S. Women’s Tackle National Team Quineshia Leonard</title>
		<summary>
			<image_path>https://assets.usafootball.com/cms/2023-04/Quineshia_Leonard_Landscape.jpg</image_path>
			<text>USA Football aims to promote football for all and create opportunities for more people to participate in the sport. Quineshia Leonard, a former collegiate women’s basketball player, started playing tackle football after being approached with an opportunity to play professionally. Leonard played as a defensive tackle for the Washington Prodigy and was later selected to play for the 2022 U.S. Women’s Tackle National Team, which won the International Federation of American Football (IFAF) Women’s World Championship. Leonard faced adversity as a travel player and mother of two, but was able to pursue her passion for football. She aims to spread women’s tackle football and provide mentorship, including creating the 757 Galaxy, a youth girls football organization.
</text>
		</summary>
		<body>USA Football emphasizes the importance of football for all and actively supports and participates in the creation of pathways for more people to participate in the sport. In the coming months, USA Football will highlight and share the experiences of exceptional members of the football community who have expanded the sport’s scope through their play.   

Quineshia Leonard, a former collegiate women’s basketball player at Norfolk State University, had long dreamed of playing basketball on the professional level, but she hung up her sneakers after graduation. Little did Leonard know there was another opportunity waiting for her in the world of tackle football.  

“I played basketball since I was nine years old. My basketball career ended before I was ready to let go,” Leonard said. “Remembering those feelings of not reaching my full potential in basketball fueled a fire in me to give football everything I had.” 

Despite not having an athletic background in football, Leonard was intrigued by the chance to play professionally when the door opened for her. 

“I started playing football after being approached with an opportunity to play professionally,” Leonard said. “I have been an athlete my entire life, and my dream has always been to be a professional athlete, so I jumped at the opportunity.” 

Leonard began her first year of organized tackle football in 2022, playing in the Women's National Football Conference as a defensive tackle for the Washington Prodigy.  

Leonard admits she had no prior knowledge of the U.S. National Team’s existence when she first started playing. The opportunity to play for the 2022 U.S. Women’s Tackle National Team was a pleasant surprise. 

“When I decided to play for the Washington Prodigy, I was told about the U.S. National Team Trials. I had no idea that there was even a National Team,” Leonard said. “When I got to the trials, it was like I was walking into a whole new world. I was surrounded by so many women who were serious about playing football. It was invigorating but it was also very intimidating. When I found out I was selected, I felt such a sense of accomplishment because there were so many talented women to choose from.” 

Leonard and the 2022 U.S. Women’s Tackle National Team captured gold at the International Federation of American Football (IFAF) Women’s World Championship in Vantaa, Finland this past summer with a 42-14 win over Great Britain in the gold medal match. The U.S. women have won gold in all four IFAF World Championships: 2010 (Sweden), 2013 (Finland), 2017 (Canada) and 2022 (Finland). 

“One of the best memories I have from my time with the U.S. National Team was hearing everyone’s story,” Leonard recalled. “Coach Callie [Brownson] had us come together to tell stories about ourselves in order to boost team camaraderie even before we came together for camp. Being able to hear about the backgrounds of other women was amazing, and it helped us connect with each other outside of just being teammates.” 

Although Leonard is one of the world’s best tackle football players, the mother of two faced some adversity finding a healthy balance between her obligations as an athlete and mother, including early skepticism about her ability to continue playing at all. However, that did not prevent her from tackling her goals head-on.  

“My entire rookie season I doubted my future in football,” Leonard said. “I am a travel player, traveling from Hampton Roads to D.C. for practices, games and events. The strain that being an unpaid athlete puts on me and my family was heavy, but the passion that I have to play football outweighed my doubts and anxiety.” 

“Finding the balance between being a good mom and pursuing my dreams has been my biggest challenge,” Leonard said. “Being a travel player requires me to miss a lot of time at home that I wouldn’t have to sacrifice if I had a team to play for locally. I have two children, five and seven, and they are at the age where they are able to understand what mommy is trying to do but they still feel the void of me being gone in order to pursue my dreams.” 

Leonard is fortunate to have had mentors pave the way for her, and now she has begun her quest to continue spreading women’s tackle football and providing mentorship.  

“I am new to women’s football, but the growth that this sport has had is hard not to see. I am blessed to be able to come into the game now when people are starting to pay attention, and I’m so grateful for all the women who have come before me for bringing women’s football to where it is now,” said Leonard. “I think that in order to continue to grow, we have to start getting the youth involved early. One of the major differences between women and men playing football is that men have been able to develop their games from the time they are five and six years old, solidifying their football foundation.” 

“Recently, I was given the opportunity to coordinate a youth girls football camp at Norfolk State University in conjunction with Got Her Back and WNFC,” Leonard explained. “After seeing the amount of girls who wanted to play football, I decided to create the 757 Galaxy. The 757 Galaxy is a youth girls football organization geared towards developing football talent as well as providing mentorship and support.” </body>
	</post>
	<post>
		<id>2</id>
		<date>4/5/2023</date>
		<author>Samuel Teets</author>
		<title>USA Football to host second annual Junior Flag International Cup</title>
		<summary>
			<image_path>https://assets.usafootball.com/cms/2023-04/DSC06964_min.jpg</image_path>
			<text>The Junior Flag International Cup, introduced by USA Football in June 2022, was an opportunity to unite young athletes from different cultures while promoting the international competitive nature of flag football. This year's event will be held from July 5-8 at the United States Performance Center and the University of North Carolina at Charlotte, coinciding with the 2023 IFAF Americas Continental Flag Football Championship. The rosters for the 2023 15U and 17U Boys' and Girls' U.S. Flag National Teams have been released, featuring 65 of the top middle school and high school athletes from 16 states. The tournament follows International Federation of American Football (IFAF) rules and promotes a consistent style of play in international competition.</text>
		</summary>
		<body>USA Football introduced the Junior Flag International Cup in June 2022. The event debuted at the University of Michigan in Ann Arbor with 15U and 17U Boys’ and Girls’ U.S. Flag National Teams facing squads fielded from Canada, Japan and Panama. It was an excellent opportunity to unite young athletes from different cultures while fostering the international competitive nature of one of the world’s fastest growing sports.  

This year’s Junior Flag International Cup will be held in a warmer climate at the United States Performance Center (USPC) and the University of North Carolina at Charlotte from July 5-8. The event coincides with the 2023 IFAF Americas Continental Flag Football Championship, featuring the U.S. Men’s and Women’s Flag National Teams.  

“The inaugural Junior Flag International Cup showed the immense potential flag football has to unite athletes from across the world, not just from across our country,” said USA Football Head of Player Personnel Charles Torwudzo. “We’re using the lessons we learned from hosting last year’s event to improve the 2023 Junior Flag International Cup. The young athletes that participate this July will walk away with incredible memories. We hope they all continue striving to improve and reach the highest level of competition as flag football becomes a regular on the international stage.” 

“Facing teams from other countries helped me tremendously in how I play today,” said 2022 17U U.S. Girls’ Flag National Team co-captain and current Women’s Flag National Team member Ashlea Klam. “Each team taught me something different and that information is very valuable to me. It also showed me how big flag football is and how it continues to grow and give opportunities to girls across the world.” “One of my favorite parts of the Junior Flag International Cup was after the tournament when I got asked to swap gear with the other teams,” Klam said. “I got Panama’s sweatpants, Canada’s game shorts, team Japan’s jersey and so much more. Everyone was so nice to each other, and you could tell that we all equally shared the love of flag football. The tournament brought me friends from around the world that I still talk to today.” 

USA Football recently released the rosters for the 2023 15U and 17U Boys’ and Girls’ U.S. Flag National Teams. Assembled through scouting, recruiting outreach and evaluation at the Junior National Team Trials, the rosters boast 65 of the top middle school and high school athletes from 16 states.  

The junior national team coaches are just as impressive as their athletes. The eight coaches (one head coach and assistant per team) have more than 120 combined years of coaching and playing experience split between flag and tackle football at the youth, high school, collegiate and professional levels.  

The Junior Flag International Cup will be played under International Federation of American Football (IFAF) rules, embracing the international governing body’s five-on-five style. This promotes a consistent style of play in international competition and prepares young athletes for IFAF events.  

Flag football’s most recent positive strides include participating at The World Games 2022, becoming the NFL Pro Bowl’s new format and receiving status as a sanctioned high school varsity sport for girls in seven states and the Southern Section of California. </body>
	</post>

	<post>
		<id>3</id>
		<date>10/17/2022</date>
		<author>Donald Robertson</author>
		<title>How I got into Stoicism</title>
		<summary>
			<image_path>https://i0.wp.com/donaldrobertson.name/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/DSCF2651-scaled.jpg</image_path>
			<text>The author, Donald Robertson, shares his background and how he became interested in philosophy and religion. He grew up in Ayr, Scotland and after his father passed away, he became interested in his old books on Freemasonic rituals which contained references to Hellenistic philosophy. However, books were hard to come by for him due to financial constraints, and he would often scour second-hand shops for any used books on philosophy. He eventually obtained a catalogue of all published books which allowed him to order specific books from the library or bookstore. His curiosity led him to learn Hebrew and read various religious texts, including Christian mystical texts and classics of Indian religion.</text>
		</summary>
		<body>People keep asking me how I got into Stoicism. Sometimes I’m asked in interviews. There’s even a guy who trolls me on the Internet making stuff up about my past. Sometimes people who Google my details get random info that’s incorrect. (My daughter thought it was hilarious that if she asked “OK Google: Who is Donald Robertson?” the computer voice would confidently inform her that I am an author, aged seventy.) So this is an attempt to set the record straight. I find it’s easier to write an account like this down in one place so if it comes up again, all I need to do is share the link. It also helps me remember all the specific details! Some of the event dates, etc., might be off by a year or so either way but, basically, this should be about as accurate as it gets. For reference, you can read most of my publication history in my Google Scholar profile.

The Beginning
I was born in Irvine, Scotland, in 1972, and grew up in the nearby town of Ayr. My father passed away when I was about thirteen years old. He didn’t leave much behind except some old books on Freemasonic rituals. I saw they mentioned symbols and ideas from the Old Testament combined with allusions to Hellenistic philosophy. I think I probably saw mention of Plato, Pythagoras, the four cardinal virtues, etc. That was what first sparked my interest in religion and philosophy. For some reason, it made me want to read more about these things.

At that time, books were hard for me to obtain. My mother, a widow, cleaned the houses of schoolteachers, and we didn’t have a lot of money. There weren’t many bookshops. I would scour second-hand shops for hours at the weekends looking for any used books on philosophy that I could find – there were extremely slim pickings available! I loved the Carnegie Library in Ayr, spent a lot of time there, and would often request books on order. One challenge was even knowing the names of books worth ordering in the first place. One day the library were selling off old books, including a huge set of Books in Print, a catalogue of all published books, which I managed to obtain. That allowed me to look up books by specific authors, which I could then try to order from the library or bookstore. This was life before the Internet!

A few years later, my curiosity piqued by some references in the Freemasonic rituals, I started learning to read Hebrew. (I didn’t get far; languages are not my forte.) A church minister lent me some books on the language. I began reading more and more obscure religious texts, including various ones on the Qabbalah – I liked modern esoteric commentators such as Aleister Crowley, Israel Regardie, Dion Fortune, but also primary sources such as Sepher Yetzirah and Sepher Zohar. I read famous Christian mystical texts like the Cloud of Uknowing, Pilgrim’s Progress, and Mystical Theology. At the same time I was also reading the classics of Indian religion, particularly the Hindu Upanishads, Bhagavad Gita, the Buddhist Dhammapada, the Tao Te Ching, and many other more obscure religious scriptures.</body>
	</post>
</blog>